Hello friends,
welcome today we are going to talk about whenever
we purchase a health policy, there are a lot of
doubts in our minds about all those
important things
today in this video I am going to tell you
which buttons you should keep in mind before buying a health policy
today I am going to
tell you all those things which no agent or
any online policy portal will
tell you or any website people
who are selling online policies or
sending help policies will not tell you today
in this video I am going to tell you many important things
so you guys stay
connected till the end of the video if you are new to the channel
then do subscribe to the channel
and like the video already so
let's start the video
[Music]
Before buying a health policy the first
point is coverage and
benefits it is
very important to know about coverage and benefits that is which
medical conditions treatment and services the
policy is providing
you have to pay attention to this and read it there is a
second in full items what is the premium what is the premium
any we buy a health policy
So the process of buying it, the
money we pay is
called premium, whatever
fees etc. are there for it is called premium,
so we should know
how much its premium is, how much its fees are and we should
buy it according to our budget, we should purchase according to our budget,
third is network
hospital, from which health insurance company we are
purchasing the policy,
with which hospitals is it panel, that is, which
hospitals are associated in its panel, so
which hospitals near us are linked
or associated with that hospital, then it is
important for us to have information about it in advance so that if
we go for treatment in any hospital near us,
then our health card can be
used there, fourth is
exclusion, what is our health policy excluding, that is, which treatment
or which disease
or someone's health issue is our health policy not covering, it is
very important for us to have information in this matter,
this is also mentioned in the policy,
waiting period, what is the waiting period,
whatever our health policy has to cover in any health policy  There is a
time period for a disease to
occur, so we
should be aware of it so that if we ever go to the hospital,
we can get its treatment in cashless mode.
If we do not know what its time
period is, then it is possible that we may face some problem
and we may have to pay for that thing at that
time. So, it is
very important for us to have prior information in this matter. Sixth
is the claim process. What happens in the claim process,
we
should know the process of our claim,
how can we use our health card
in the claim, what
documents do we need for it, what
documents will be required for it and what
kind of treatment can we get through it. It is
very important for us to have this information in advance.
Seventh point, payment means
paying it yourself. When
we are admitted in the hospital, even if the final bill is
sent for approval, then there is some
deduction in it, that has to be paid in the form of dictation. So, regarding
this copayment,
we should know in advance
what percentage copayment is there in our policy
that we will have to pay.
We should definitely know that beforehand. The
eighth is the free
existing condition. What this means is that
before buying a health policy, if we already have
any disease, then we have to
tell the health insurance policy. If
we do not tell then our insurance gets delayed
and if we tell in advance then there is a
difference in the premium. So
we should know about that thing beforehand
and at the time of purchase, we should tell our agent or any
website from which we are purchasing online about the
thing in advance, it is
beneficial for us only. If
we want to buy any health insurance, then
we should know about the insurance company's
reviews and what reviews the customers are giving for it. If we go online and look, there are
many websites where
we can
read customer reviews about that company, so on that basis
we can decide whether this company
is good and we should buy it. The
tenth point is that there are
some items
whose expenses the insurance company does
not pass. These are loan payable sites,
which items, apart from marriage, are
also not available in regular life.  Banda can use it
like cotton roll, diaper, season, there
are many such things
which any person can use in normal life, but the
health insurance
company never passes its cost
and its money
comes in non-tables because agents and online websites do not tell about
this thing in detail
and later when our claim is
settled, there is a deduction in it, then it
seems big to us and we feel that the
website people, online website people
and the agent have cheated us, so these were the 10
points which I told you today, if you have any question in this matter,
apart from these 10 points, if you have any question in your mother, then
write in the comment area, if you liked the video then
like and subscribe to the channel, we will meet
in the next video, till then hello